Guide to the Cornell University pamphlet collection, circa 1870-1918.
Cornell University pamphlet collection
- "Financial Assistance and Self Help at Cornell University", 1914; 13; no. 14
- "How Cornell Does It," a reprinted article from The Boston Transcript, 1911; 13; no. 15
- "Frosh ABC's," the Corner Book's Cornell Book, written and illustrated by Horace W. Peaslee, 1911; 13; no. 16
- "The Co-Op; Pass the Word Along," printed by Morrill Hall, Cornell University, 1914; 13; no. 17
- "Rooms Available in Ithaca 1914-1915", July, 1914; 13; no. 18
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, 1911; 13; no. 19
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, 1912; 13; no. 20
- "Manual of Information Together with Notes on Exercise and Personal Hygiene," by the Department of Physical Training, Cornell University, 1913; 13; no. 21
- "Memorial of John B. Yates, relative to the Literary Institute in Chittenango," addressed to the New York State Senate, January, 1830; 14; no. 1
- "Petition of the Genesee Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church," addressed to the New York State Assembly, January, 1834; 14; no. 2
- "Report of the Committee on Agriculture, on so much of the Governor's message as relates to the establishment of a board of agriculture; and also, several petitions, praying for the establishment of an agricultural school," addressed to the New York State Senate, March, 1834; 14; no. 3
- "Fifth Annual Report of the American Institute," addressed to the New York State Legislature, 1847; 14; no. 4
- "Report of the committee on colleges, academies, and common schools, on an agricultural and scientific school and experimental farm," addressed to the New York State Assembly, April, 1847; 14; no. 5
- "Report of the committee on agriculture, relative to an experimental farm and agricultural school," addressed to the New York State Assembly, May, 1847; 14; no. 6
- "Report of the Committee on colleges, academies and common schools, relative to the establishment of an experimental farm, and workshop for mechanical operations, and a school for the promotion of agriculture and the mechanical arts," addressed to the New York State Assembly, September, 1847; 14; no. 7
- "Memorial on behalf of the New-York State Agricultural Society, for the establishment of an Agricultural School," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1849; 14; no. 8
- "Governor's Message" to the New York State Legislature, including the appointment of "a board of commissioners to mature a plan for the establishment of an Agricultural College and Experimental Farm", January, 1850; 14; no. 9
- "Report of the special committee on the agricultural college and experimental farm," addressed to the New York State Assembly, March, 1850; 14; no. 10
- "Memorial of the Genesee College in relation to Agricultural School," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1850; 14; no. 11
- "Report of the Committee on Agriculture on so much of the Governor's Message as relates to an Agricultural College and Mechanical School, and on the Memorial of the State Agricultural Society on the same subject," addressed to the New York State Assembly, January, 1851; 14; no. 12
- "Report of the minority of the committee on the subject of an Agricultural College and Experimental Farm," addressed to the New York State Assembly, March, 1851; 14; no. 13
- "Report of the committee on agriculture on so much of the Governor's message as relates to an Agricultural Institution and an experimental farm," addressed to the New York State Assembly, March, 1852; 14; no. 14
- "Report of the Committee on Agriculture to establish an Agricultural School, etc.," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1853; 14; no. 15
- "Report of the minority of the Committee on Agriculture, on the bill to incorporate the People's College," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1853; 14; no. 16
- "Report of the Committee on Agriculture to establish an Agricultural School, etc.," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1853; 14; no. 17
- "Report of the minority of the Committee on Agriculture, on the bill to incorporate the People's College," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1853; 14; no. 18
- "Report of the Regents of the University on Military Instruction in the Colleges of Higher Institutions of Learning, in the State, in Response to the Resolution of the Assembly of January 24th, 1862," addressed to the New York State Assembly, March, 1862; 14; no. 19
- "Report of the committee on finance upon petitions for aid to establish the New-York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Senate, March, 1855; 14; no. 20
- "Memorial of the trustees and friends of the New-York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Assembly, February, 1855; 14; no. 21
- "Report of the Finance Committee, on petitions asking aid to establish the New-York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Senate, January, 1856; 14; no. 22
- "Annual Report of the Trustees of the New York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Assembly, January, 1860; 14; no. 23
- "Report of the Committee on Literature, on the petition for aid to Genesee College," addressed to the New York State Senate, February, 1860; 14; no. 24
- "Annual Report of the Trustees of the New York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Assembly, January, 1861; 14; no. 25
- "Report of the Trustees of the New York State Agricultural College, at Ovid," addressed to the New York State Assembly, March, 1863; 14; no. 26
- "Communication from the Comptroller Relative to the Agricultural College," with a general statement of the financial condition of the New York State Agricultural College, addressed to the New York State Senate, February, 1865; 14; no. 27
- Annual Report from the New York State Agricultural Society (incomplete), 1861; 14; no. 28
- "Communication from the Regents of the University in Answer to a Resolution of the 4th Instant, Relative to the People's College at Havana," addressed to the New York State Senate, February, 1865; 14; no. 29
- Statistics on the agricultural yield and work of Tompkins County in 1860 by Ezra Cornell, 1860; 14; no. 30
- "Report of the Trustees of the New York State Agricultural College," addressed to the New York State Senate, March, 1864; 14; no. 31
- "A Letter to the Alumni" from Alpha Delta Phi at Cornell University, with statements on the chapter's finances, April, 1914; 15; no. 1
- "Annual Report of the Cornell University Chapter, the Beta Delta of Beta Theta Pi," with alumni directory, 1900; 15; no. 2
- "Annual Report of the Cornell University Chapter, the Beta Delta of Beta Theta Pi," with alumni directory, 1901; 15; no. 3
- "Annual Report of the Cornell University Chapter, the Beta Delta of Beta Theta Pi," with alumni directory, 1902; 15; no. 4
- "Annual Report of the Cornell University Chapter, the Beta Delta of Beta Theta Pi," with alumni directory, 1904; 15; no. 5
- "Report of the Board of Trustees and of the Active Chapter" for the Beta Delta of Beta Theta Pi, with alumni directory, 1909; 15; no. 6
- Annual letter to the alumni from the Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon, including a list and photograph of members, June, 1910; 15; no. 7
- "A Letter to the Alumni [from the] Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon," including a list and photograph of members, May, 1914; 15; no. 8
- Annual letter to the alumni from the Cornell Chapter of Delta Upsilon, including a list and photograph of members, May, 1915; 15; no. 9
- "Proceedings of the Eighty-first Annual Convention of the Delta Upsilon Fraternity Held with the Cornell Chapter", 1915; 15; no. 10
- Pamphlet from "Gamma Theta of Sigma Nu," including chapter history and list of members' addresses, c. 1910; 15; no. 11
- Statement of policy and practice from the Cornell University Graduate School, 1912; 15; no. 12
- "Digest and Index of Legislation by the Faculty of the Graduate School 1909-1915", 1914; 15; no. 13
- "Some Problems of the Graduate School; an Informal Report to the Faculty," written by its dean, J.E. Creighton, 1915; 15; no. 14
- "Problems of the Graduate School; an Informal Report by the Dean [J.E. Creighton] to the Members of the Faculty", 1916; 15; no. 15
- "Study for a Research Laboratory," reprinted from the Sibley Journal of Mechanical Engineering, February, 1902, 1902; 15; no. 16
- Announcement and program for the Physical Education courses at the State College of Agriculture as part of the Cornell University Summer Session, 1918; 15; no. 17
- "Information Concerning the University Club, Incorporated of Ithaca, New York", c. 1914; 15; no. 18
- A letter to the alumnae from and the constitution of the College Settlements Association, c. 1889; 15; no. 19
- "How the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University Is Meeting the Veterinary Needs of the State and Country," by V.A. Moore, its dean, 1917; 15; no. 20
- Notice with information on "The Professorial Pension Fund", 1903; 15; no. 21
- "Items of Business for Agricultural College Council for its Meeting May 2, 1913", May, 1913; 15; no. 22
- "Report of a Committee of the University Faculty on the Establishment of a Commercial Course of Instruction at Cornell University", 1914; 15; no. 23
- "Report to the University Faculty" about statements by President Schurman and letters from the Cornell University Association of Chicago addressed to him, May, 1918; 15; no. 24
- "Report of the University Faculty to the Board of Trustees in Regard to the Office of Adviser of Women", 1917; 15; no. 25
- Confidential "Reply of Cornell University to the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Learning," with financial statistics on the proposition(, March, 1916; 15; no. 26
- Report by a faculty committee of the Cornell University College of Law, on a proposal to change the entrance requirements from one year of college work to two years; and on a proposal to lengthen the professional law course to four years, 1916; 15; no. 27
- "[Exercise and Song] Selections for the Classes in Voice Training in the Department of Oratory", c. 1900; 15; no. 28
- Information manual for the "Students' Army Training Corps," with a general statement of regulations and programs, October, 1918; 15; no. 29
- "Outline of a Course on Water Rights under the Appropriation System," by L. Ward Bannister, 1915; 15; no. 30
- "Syllabus of the Course in Citizenship" for the second term with schedule of lecture speakers and abstracts, 1914-1915; 15; no. 31
- The Phi Beta Kappa Key, published by the Unionist-Gazette Association, vol. II, no. 12, including the article, "The Theta Chapter of New York at Cornell," by Clark S. Northup, May, 1916; 15; no. 32
- Circular by the Alumni Athletic Field Committee on the assurance of a "New Athletic Field", July 31, 1903; 16; no. 1
- Letter by Geo. W. Bacon, chairman of the Alumni Athletic Field Committee, on supporting the Alumni Field Equipment Fund, June 1, 1908; 16; no. 2
- "Alumni Field, Cornell University: Seventh Annual Report [on the] Alumni and Trustees' Committees", May 6, 1908; 16; no. 3
- "Alumni Field, Cornell University: Eighth Annual Report [on the] Alumni and Trustees' Committees", June 14, 1909; 16; no. 4
- "Alumni Field, Cornell University: Ninth Annual Report [on the] Alumni and Trustees' Committees", June 22, 1910; 16; no. 5
- "Vereinigung Alter Deutscher Studenten in Amerika [No.21]", January, 1909; 16; no. 6
- "'Comparative Length of Term Time in the Leading American Universities,' a Report of Committee of Cornell University Faculty", [1909?]; 16; no. 7
- University academic calendar with outlines of first and second semesters, [1909?]; 16; no. 8
- "Schedule of Examinations, 1908-1909," from June 1st to 9th, 1908; 16; no. 9
- "Scedule of Examinations, 1909-1910," from January 17th to 26th and June 6th to 14th, 1909; 16; no. 10
- Blank form for written responses on the effectiveness of the "Arts Pamphlet," information pamphlet on the College of Arts and Sciences, 1909; 16; no. 11
- Blank form for "Communication to the Faculty," i.e. the making of petitions, [1909?]; 16; no. 12
- Blank form for written responses on the proposal to offer graduate work in the Summer Session, 1909; 16; no. 13
- Facsimile of Alumni Trusteeship petition to nominate Charles Courter Dickinson, Class of 1891, to be ballotted for election of Alumni Trustee, 1909; 16; no. 14
- "Biographical Sketch of Charles C. Dickinson," with printed engraving, 1909; 16; no. 15
- Circular endorsing the election of James H. Edwards to the position of Alumni Trustee, March 27, 1906; 16; no. 16
- Circular endorsing the election of Charles C. Dickinson to the position of Alumni Trustee, 1909; 16; no. 17
- Circular endorsing the election of Charles C. Dickinson to the position of Alumni Trustee, April 5, 1909; 16; no. 18
- "Biographical Sketches of Candidates [for Alumni Trustee] Furnished by the Corresponding Secretary of the Associate Alumni", 1909; 16; no. 19
- Biographical sketch of Miss Ethel Stebbins, Alumni Trustee candidate, by Evelyn Andrews Burcher, 1909; 16; no. 20
- Letter from Dean L. Kelsey, general secretary of the Cornell University Christian Association, addressed to A. C. White, November 22, 1909; 16; no. 21
- Letter from Dean L. Kelsey, general secretary of the Cornell University Christian Association, addressed to A. C. White, May 11, 1910; 16; no. 22
- Advertisement for a "General Reunion of all Cornellians, 1868-1908", 1908; 16; no. 23
- "Needs of the New York State Colleges at Cornell University," presented by the Trustees, January, 1910; 16; no. 24
- Program for the "Poultry Institute and Educational Exhibits" for "Farmers' Week at Cornell", 1910; 16; no. 25
- Guide sheet for the Annual Fruit Exhibit, presented by the students of the College of Agriculture, 1909; 16; no. 26
- "1905 Cornell Country-Man Calendar", 1905; 16; no. 27
- "The Cornell Expedition to Asia Minor and the Assyro-Babylonian Orient Organized by Prof. J.R.S. Sterrett [Second Report]", January 6, 1908; 16; no. 28
- "The Cornell Expedition to Asia Minor and the Assyro-Babylonian Orient Organized by Prof. J.R.S. Sterrett [Third Report]", March 30, 1908; 16; no. 29
- "Report of the Committee on Improvement of Salaries," submitted to the Cornell Club of Northern California, [1908?]; 16; no. 30
- Blank questionnaire from the Cornell Association of Class Secretaries, 1905; 16; no. 31
- Memorandum on financial assistance [to students], February, 1909; 16; no. 32
- "Philobiblon" [Love of Books], by Ricardi de Bury, Episcopi Dunelmensis, [1902?]; 16; no. 33
- Pamphlet by the Committee on Alumni Hall of "Competitive Designs" for the Alumni Hall project, April 15, 1899; 16; no. 34
- Program for the General Meeting of the Archaeological Institute of America and the Annual Meeting of the American Philological Association, 1905; 16; no. 35
- "Program of the Thirty-fourth General Meeting of the American Chemical Society", 1906; 16; no. 36
- Letter from the Secretary of the Quill and Dagger to fraternity brothers, requesting subscriptions for the Hall Fund, 1905; 16; no. 37
- Science, [periodical], vol. XXIV, no. 602, including "The American Association for the Advancement of Science", July 13, 1906; 16; no. 38
- "Retirement of Professor Simon Henry Gage from the Chair of Histology and Embryology in Cornell University," reprinted from The Anatomical Record, vol. II, no. 7, 1908; 16; no. 39
- Program for the "Cornell University Forty-Second Annual Commencement", 1910; 16; no. 40
- Science [periodical], vol. XXVIII, no. 725, including "Abstracts from the Annual Report of the President of Cornell University", November 20, 1908; 16; no. 41
- The Welcome [periodical], vol. VII, no. 1, "In Memoriam [of] William Holmes Nichols", January, 1907; 16; no. 42
- Cornell Alumni Ooze [periodical], vol. I, no. 1, "Published for the Gentle Merriment of all Cornellians", June 16, 1908; 16; no. 43